## **Lalit Kumar**

Senior Software Engineer







Email: lk.iitkgp@gmail.com

Web: https://lkiitkgp.github.io/me/



#### About Me



Hi, my name is Lalit and I'm a senior software engineer. I have 2 years+ experience in making softwares. I have worked at two companies gaining technical, teamwork, and leadership skills.

I am most skilled in: Node.js and DevOps

Frameworks: Express Django Databases: MongoDB MSSQL

Programming Languages: JavaScript Java Python Groovy

Softwares & CI/CD Tools: Docker Jenkins Azure Gitlab BitBucket GitHub Actions Jira AWS

### Experience

HCL Software
Senior Software Engineer
September 2020 - Present

www.hcltechsw.com/accelerate

- Core Team (June 2022 Present): I'm part of the core team for HCL Accelerate (UrbanCode Velocity) and am responsible for delivering enhancements and bug fixes. Besides this, I groom new members, guide Plugins Team, and maintain Automated Release Process for Plugins Team
- Plugins Team (Sept. 2020 May 2022): I was part of the Plugins Development Team for HCL Accelerate and HCL Launch (UrbanCode Deploy). I worked on creating new plugins and maintaining already existing plugins
- · Performance Reviews: 1st Year | 2nd Year

Perpule, Bangalore Software Development Intern May 2019 - July 2019

blog.perpule.com

- Developed payment microservice using Rest API, Cloud SQL, Google App Engine. Reducing transaction latency by 83%
- Responsible for adding new payment methods, code-refactoring, optimizations adhering to the testing, delivering to the production team

#### Education

Established in 1951, the institute is the first of the IITs to be established and is recognised as an Institute of National Importance. In 2019 it was awarded the status of Institute of Eminence by the Government of India

# Indian Institue of Technology, Kharagpur B.Tech. + M.Tech.

CGPA 7.33 2015 - 2020 Master's Thesis Dissertation: Propeller Characteristics Generation Software

Objective: Develope software for generating open water characteristics of BSeries ship propeller using python

Bachelor's Thesis Dissertation: Data Analytics for Condition-based Maintenance

Objective: Improving condition-based maintenance of the Combined Diesel electric and Gas propulsion plant of a naval vessel using various data analytics and machine learning approaches

I spent a lot of my free time as a student senate member of the *IIT Kharagpur* taking on roles such as *Hall President* and *General Secretary* for *Nehru Hall of Residence* 

## A Little More About Me

Alongside my interest in software engineering some of my other interests and hobbies are:

- Cooking
- Playing Chess